Last week, friends, we saw how
you can buy bike insurance using the Policy Bazaar mobile app.
In today's video, I'll
explain how to download
any insurance policy you've purchased from Policy Bazaar in the past
and can't find its PDF
or policy document. I'll also explain
how to
track your claim status if
you haven't received your policy document, or if
your money has been deducted twice, how to
raise a request, or how to file a
claim with different insurance companies, or what
their contact
details are. Overall, we'll explain
how to use the Policy Bazaar app. If
you've purchased an insurance policy from here, we'll cover everything from
logging into the Policy Bazaar mobile app to downloading the policy
and using its various features.
If you want to understand the ins and outs of using the Policy Bazaar app,
watch the video until the end.
If you gain any additional information or knowledge,
it will definitely come in handy at some point.  If it
comes, let's not delay and
let's quickly start the video.
First of all, friends, we have to search for [music] on our mobile phone.
Why is this because
when we log in to the app using our mobile number,
a user ID is created for us.
Whatever policy we
buy after logging in with this mobile number gets
mapped to the policies in our account.
Whenever we
log in with this mobile number in the future, we will find
those policies in our database as it is.
So we log in here with the registered mobile number. To
log in, we will
enter the mobile number, which
after auto-fetching, automatically logs in to the app.
After this, friends, you will
see a user interface like this here. Now, at the
bottom, you will see the items of the venue.
Here, in the center, it is written '
Policies'. We will click here.
After clicking here, you will
see two options above - Active and Inactive
Policies. What does this mean? Active policies are
those which are still active, that is, those whose
risk coverage is still active, their
validity still remains.  These
policies have not expired,
which are the incto policies, which you had bought in the past
but these have expired,
you will also get the record of them inside this app, so
first of all friends, click on the
active policy which is visible here
and here
you will see the option of download policy at the top, as soon as you
click on it, this policy will be
downloaded in your file manager,
after that you can open it from there, two wheeler
details, owner details, nominee details,
you will see all the details here,
you can check whose
policy is this, what are the details
of the owner of the two wheeler and the nominee, the option '
Need Help' is visible at the bottom, this is a very important option, let us
click on it and see what
options we get for help, so
here the option is coming, raise a request, for
what thing the request will be raised, if
you are facing any problem, then
you can raise its request from here,
what kind of problems can arise,
any payment related problem can happen, like
if your money
If your premium has been deducted twice,
meaning your money has been deducted twice,
you should receive a one-time refund.
You can also raise that request from here.
This is a request from the time you
purchased the policy. If you face any problem after that, you can raise that request here. Go
back to the menu and you
can raise the second request: Need a
Copy. If you need a hard copy, you want a hard copy sent to
your address via a letter. You can raise
your request by clicking on Need Policy Hard Copy. The
second option is
Need Policy Soft Copy. If you have
n't received the soft copy, or PDF, that
option is also provided here. By clicking on this second
request, you can
also raise your PDF request here.
If you have received the PDF
but it won't open, the file
is corrupt, or blank, a third option
is provided. Click on it.  You can also raise a request by doing this and
a valid
PDF will be sent to you again. Now this
was about active policies, but if you suppose
you had a policy that you bought a year or two
ago but now you need its PDF or
soft copy, then you
can also get it from here. For example,
open the two-wheeler shown at the top,
its last policy of 2021-22
is also available here. If you want to download it, there is an
option to download policy copy here.
We can download it from here.
Why might you need an old policy copy? It is
possible that a
claim has come under the latest insurance policy and now your
surveyor may have asked you for your previous policy
and you may not have its PDF. In
this way, you
can also download the policy PDF of previous years from here. If you
click on the option to download policy copy, then your policy
copy will also be downloaded from here. From here, go back
and explore the rest of the menu.
Now, in this way,
you can also download all the active policies.  You can download from here
any vehicle
policy that you have had in the past. Now you
can track the claim using the option on the side, like
clicking on Track Claim.
You can also check the status of all your registered claims from
here. For example, there was a
recent claim which is shown as 'Case Close' here.
Click on it and see that
this claim was filed in the past for
this vehicle number.
You
can also check the status of the claim from here by clicking on Track Status. Now, since this
case is already closed, the status is already
closed here. But if you have any
ongoing claim, you can also check its status by
clicking on Track Status here,
whether it is a two-wheeler claim or a
car claim. Let's go back.
Apart from this, if
you need the contact details of your insurance company,
you can also get that from here.
Click on Contact and Insure. That means, you can get the
contact details of your insurance company from here.
You can get the
policy document from here.  There's no need to even look for it.
Click on Contact and Insure.
After that, you'll have to
select the product and which policy
you're looking for. Suppose I'm
looking for a car insurance policy, a
list of insurance companies appears here.
I can get the contact details of my insurance company from here.
Suppose I select ADF Surgo, then
look, the ADF Surgo
contact number, which is their toll-free number,
and their email ID, as well as their customer care
email ID, are also displayed here.
If you need
help from customer care,
you can get that information from here. So, what
we've seen here is how you can access the claims center,
how you can download the policy,
how you can raise a policy-related request.
You can also download past year policies,
and if
you have any queries related to them, you can raise a request for that too.
If you've purchased any policy from Policy Bazaar,
you can avail services related to your past policy in this way.
You've understood the entire process through the video. So,
friends,
you don't have to pay any extra money for any of these services you've seen. If
you've purchased a policy from any insurance company
through the Policy Bazaar app,
you can use these different services this way.
If you're
unfamiliar with these features, then even if they're in the app, they're useless
because if you do
n't know how to use them, they're of no use to us.
So, we learned
how to use the features provided within the app
and
how to track requests, policy downloads, and claims, all from
our phone
devices without anyone else's help. I hope
this video has
enhanced your knowledge and created some value for you.
If you feel
you liked or understood this information,
you can like and share the video to show your love and support.
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet,
please do subscribe.
I, Harvinder Singh, now take your permission. I'll get your
permission in the next video. Until then, take
care.  Stay happy
and healthy, Jai Hind